<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Open Modeling Foundation</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on The Open Modeling Foundation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Community</title><link>/about/community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/community/</guid><description>Member Organizations and Representatives Representatives of member organizations make up the Members Council, the primary governing body of the Open Modeling Foundation. They are responsible for approving policies, procedures, and standards.
Any formally constituted organization composed of or representing an active community of modelers in the social and natural sciences may request to become a member of the Open Modeling Foundation and join the Members Council by addressing a letter of request to the Executive Committee.</description></item><item><title>Members Council</title><link>/about/members-council/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/members-council/</guid><description>Agricultural Model Intercomparison and Improvement Project (AgMIP)
American Geophysical Union (AGU)
Analysis, Integration, and Modeling of the Earth System, Future Earth (AIMES)
SDSU Center for Climate and Sustainability Studies (C2S2)
Center for Open Science (COS)
Centre for Policy Modelling, Manchester Metropolitan University Business School
Community for Data Integration and Model Catalog, US Geological Survey (CDI-USGS)
Community Surface Dynamics Modeling System (CSDMS)
Network for Computational Modeling in Social and Ecological Systems (CoMSES)</description></item><item><title>Events and Activities</title><link>/about/history-events-and-activities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 10:34:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>/about/history-events-and-activities/</guid><description>Upcoming Activities Information on activities or projects of individual OMF Working Groups can be found within their individual pages accessed via the Working Groups page.
December 2024 Virtual Members Council Meeting
May 2025 Members Council Meeting
Past Activities May 2024 Members Council Meeting Election of initial Executive Committee representatives (January 2022) Founding Meeting of the Open Modeling Foundation Meeting to formally establish the Open Modeling Foundation
2021, December 6 - 8: Hybrid meeting at ASU in Washington DC and online videoconference</description></item><item><title>Open Modeling Foundation Values</title><link>/about/values/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 10:34:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>/about/values/</guid><description>Our Values The Open Modeling Foundation is an international open science community made up of diverse scientists and teams from around the world who seek to meet the planetary, social, and environmental challenges we face in our complex and rapidly changing world. As members of the Open Modeling Foundation, we champion collaborative and open science. Our community and our mission are strengthened through diverse perspectives and the exchange of ideas in an inclusive environment.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>/about/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 19:20:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>Ratified: October 2023 This Code of Conduct was approved October 20th 2023 by the Members Council of the Open Modeling Foundation. The Open Modeling Foundation (OMF) is an international open science community of diverse scientists and teams from around the world seeking to meet the planetary, social, and environmental challenges we face in our complex and rapidly changing world. As members of the Open Modeling Foundation, we champion collaborative and open science.</description></item><item><title>Call for International Translation of Standards and Site Content</title><link>/contribute/call-for-translators/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 10:34:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>/contribute/call-for-translators/</guid><description>Deadline This page will be updated with a deadline soon.
OMF is looking for Translators / Interpreters to assist in translating standards and website content. The selected volunteer translators and interpreters will work with OMF on project to translate OMF content and standards amd promote international accessibility.
Eligibility Open to professional or voluntary translators and interpreters Must have previous work experience as translator or interpreter (professional or volunteer, paid or unpaid) Be a Translator / Interpreter in any of the following languages:</description></item><item><title>Certification Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/certification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/certification/</guid><description>The Certification Working Group (CWG) develops and administers programs to certify model code that meets OMF standards for modeling best practices, and officially recognize model developers who apply these standards. CWG activities include developing and administering a community-wide program for model code peer review, establishing metrics for standards compliance, creating and assigning digital certification badges that follow guidelines being developed by the National Information Standards Organization (NISO). The CWG helps OMF member (and other) code repositories to ensure that models meeting OMF standards are clearly identified and developers who create standards-based models are publicly recognized.</description></item><item><title>Cyberinfrastructure Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/cyberinfrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/cyberinfrastructure/</guid><description>The Cyberinfrastructure Working Group (CYWG) coordinates development and management of the OMF Science Gateway, an online platform for collaborative governance and standards. CYWG works to to identify, develop, and enhance tools and processes that lower the technical barriers towards adoption of OMF standards and facilitate their use by modeling scientists. CYWG staff assist the EOWG in developing online training modules and making them available on the OMF Science Gateway.
If you are interested in joining the Cyberinfrastructure Working Group, please use this link or reach our to the group Chair for further information.</description></item><item><title>Early Career Scholars Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/early-career-scholars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/early-career-scholars/</guid><description>The Early Career Scholars (ECSWG) helps the Open Modeling Foundation to support student and early career development. The ECSWG is open to any student enrolled in an institution of higher learning (e.g., college or university) or early career scholar (recent graduate). The ECSWG provides input to the Executive Committee. The ECSWG can organize student-focused programs, manuscripts, and events, assisted by the Administrative Coordinator and other OMF WG&amp;rsquo;s as appropriate.
If you are interested in joining the Early Career Scholars Working Group, please use this link or reach out to the group Chair for further information.</description></item><item><title>Education and Outreach Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/education-and-outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/education-and-outreach/</guid><description>The Education and Outreach Working Group (EOWG) helps OMF member organizations reach and train next generation scholars and ensure proactive outreach to groups and nationalities that are underrepresented in modeling science. Depending on available resources, it may develop and deploy educational and training materials, organize workshops, symposia, clinics, and other promotional or engagement events to disseminate OMF standards and help modeling scientists meet those standards. The EOWG coordinates with the SWG to ensure that standards adopted by the OMF are supported by appropriate training and educational programs, and accessible via the OMF Science Gateway.</description></item><item><title>Executive Committee Meeting Agendas</title><link>/about/executive-committee/meetings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/executive-committee/meetings/</guid><description>Recent Executive Committee Meeting Agenda Documents
2026
2025
2025 Meeting 1 February 2025 Meeting 2 March 2025 Meeting 3 March 2025 Meeting 4 June 2025 Meeting 5 September 2025 Meeting 6 November</description></item><item><title>Archived Meeting Agendas</title><link>/about/executive-committee/archived-agendas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/executive-committee/archived-agendas/</guid><description>2024
2024 Meeting 1 January 2024 Meeting 2 February 2024 Meeting 3 March 2024 Meeting 4 April 2024 Meeting 5 May 2024 Meeting 6 July 2024 Meeting 7 September 2024 Meeting 8 October 2024 Meeting 9 November 2024 Meeting 10 December 2023
2023 Meeting 1 January 2023 Meeting 2 February 2023 Meeting 3 April 2023 Meeting 4 May 2023 Meeting 5 June 2023 Meeting 6 September 2023 Meeting 7 November 2023 Meeting 8 December 2022 Executive Committee Meeting Agenda Documents</description></item><item><title>Standards Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/standards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/standards/</guid><description>Overview The Standards Working Group (SWG) oversees the adoption, dissemination, and administration of Open Modeling Foundation standards for access, documentation, reusability, and interoperability. It proposes standards to be reviewed, revised, and approved by the OMF Members Council. The SWG works with Administrative Coordinator to communicate proposed and adopted OMF standards to OMF member organizations and other stakeholders, and solicit input about proposed standards from the modeling community. In coordination with the Certification Working Group, it helps OMF member (and other) code repositories implement OMF standards for access, discoverability, and recognition of model developers who implement OMF best practice standards.</description></item></channel></rss>