<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Open Modeling Foundation – Governance</title><link>/governance/</link><description>Recent content in Governance on The Open Modeling Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Governance: Working Groups</title><link>/governance/working-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 09:43:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>/governance/working-groups/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="working-groups">Working Groups&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many Open Modeling Foundation activities are guided by Working Groups. Any modeling scientist can join a Working Group. Working Groups will self organize, and nominate a Working Group Chair, for approval by the Members Council. Working Group Chairs serve for a three-year, renewable term.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="standards-working-group">Standards Working Group&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Standards Working Group oversees the adoption, dissemination, and administration of Open Modeling Foundation standards for access, documentation, reusability, and interoperability; it may also propose additional standards. It proposes standards to be reviewed, revised, and approved by the Open Modeling Foundation membership. The Standards Working Group helps to communicate Open Modeling Foundation standards to member organizations and other stakeholders, and solicit input from the modeling community. It also establishes procedures to evaluate and certify model code that meets Open Modeling Foundation standards, working with code repositories and scientific software journals to ensure that code review includes Open Modeling Foundation criteria and that any Open Modeling Foundation digital badges are awarded for models that comply with these standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="cyberinfrastructure-working-group">Cyberinfrastructure Working Group&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Cyberinfrastructure Working Group serves to identify or develop tools and processes which serve to lower the technical barriers towards adoption of the standards developed by the Standards Working Group. The Cyberinfrastructure Working Group also identifies ways to best deploy these tools and sufficient documentation to enable their use to modeling scientists. This Working Group also coordinates the development and management of the Open Modeling Foundation Science Gateway. The Cyberinfrastructure Working Group may be assisted by Open Modeling Foundation technical staff in its mission. Open Modeling Foundation technical staff will be defacto members of the Cyberinfrastructure Working Group.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="outreach-and-education-working-group">Outreach and Education Working Group&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Outreach and Education Working Group coordinates collaborative efforts with journals, funding agencies, societies, institutions/labs, other software/modeling consortia to disseminate and administer Open Modeling Foundation standards across the community of modeling science. Depending on available resources, it also may develop and deploy educational and training materials, organize workshops, symposia, clinics, and other promotional or engagement events to disseminate Open Modeling Foundation standards and help modeling scientists meet those standards. It is specifically charged with helping the Open Modeling Foundation members reach and train next generation scholars and ensure proactive outreach to groups and nationalities that are underrepresented in modeling science.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="additional-working-groups">Additional Working Groups&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Other Working Groups may be proposed by the Executive Directorate to oversee and coordinate additional Open Modeling Foundation activities. The establishment of any new working groups must be approved by the Open Modeling Foundation membership.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>