<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on The Open Modeling Foundation</title><link>/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on The Open Modeling Foundation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Community</title><link>/about/community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/community/</guid><description>Member Organizations and Representatives Representatives of member organizations make up the Members Council, the primary governing body of the Open Modeling Foundation. They are responsible for approving policies, procedures, and standards.
Any formally constituted organization composed of or representing an active community of modelers in the social and natural sciences may request to become a member of the Open Modeling Foundation and join the Members Council by addressing a letter of request to the Executive Committee.</description></item><item><title>Members Council</title><link>/about/members-council/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/members-council/</guid><description>Agricultural Model Intercomparison and Improvement Project (AgMIP)
American Geophysical Union (AGU)
Analysis, Integration, and Modeling of the Earth System, Future Earth (AIMES)
SDSU Center for Climate and Sustainability Studies (C2S2)
Center for Open Science (COS)
Centre for Policy Modelling, Manchester Metropolitan University Business School
Community for Data Integration and Model Catalog, US Geological Survey (CDI-USGS)
Community Surface Dynamics Modeling System (CSDMS)
Network for Computational Modeling in Social and Ecological Systems (CoMSES)</description></item><item><title>Events and Activities</title><link>/about/history-events-and-activities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 10:34:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>/about/history-events-and-activities/</guid><description>Upcoming Activities Information on activities or projects of individual OMF Working Groups can be found within their individual pages accessed via the Working Groups page.
December 2024 Virtual Members Council Meeting
May 2025 Members Council Meeting
Past Activities May 2024 Members Council Meeting Election of initial Executive Committee representatives (January 2022) Founding Meeting of the Open Modeling Foundation Meeting to formally establish the Open Modeling Foundation
2021, December 6 - 8: Hybrid meeting at ASU in Washington DC and online videoconference</description></item><item><title>Open Modeling Foundation Values</title><link>/about/values/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 10:34:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>/about/values/</guid><description>Our Values The Open Modeling Foundation is an international open science community made up of diverse scientists and teams from around the world who seek to meet the planetary, social, and environmental challenges we face in our complex and rapidly changing world. As members of the Open Modeling Foundation, we champion collaborative and open science. Our community and our mission are strengthened through diverse perspectives and the exchange of ideas in an inclusive environment.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>/about/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 19:20:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>Ratified: October 2023 This Code of Conduct was approved October 20th 2023 by the Members Council of the Open Modeling Foundation. The Open Modeling Foundation (OMF) is an international open science community of diverse scientists and teams from around the world seeking to meet the planetary, social, and environmental challenges we face in our complex and rapidly changing world. As members of the Open Modeling Foundation, we champion collaborative and open science.</description></item></channel></rss>