<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Open Modeling Foundation – Working Groups</title><link>/about/working-groups/</link><description>Recent content in Working Groups on The Open Modeling Foundation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/about/working-groups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About: Certification Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/certification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/certification/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Certification Working Group (CWG) develops and administers programs to certify model code that meets OMF standards for modeling best practices, and officially recognize model developers who apply these standards. CWG activities include developing and administering a community-wide program for model code peer review, establishing metrics for standards compliance, creating and assigning digital certification badges that follow guidelines being developed by the National Information Standards Organization (NISO). The CWG helps OMF member (and other) code repositories to ensure that models meeting OMF standards are clearly identified and developers who create standards-based models are publicly recognized. The CWG coordinates collaborative efforts with journals, funding agencies, societies, institutions/labs, other software/modeling consortia, and professional bodies to disseminate and administer OMF standards across the community of modeling science, and to promote recognition of OMF standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in joining the Certification Working Group,
&lt;a href="https://asu.questionpro.com/omf-wg-joinrequest">please use this link&lt;/a> or reach out to any of the group Co-Chairs for further information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/openmodelingfoundation/openmodelingfoundation.github.io/discussions/categories/wg-certification">Contribute to the Certification Working Group discussion on GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="certification-co-chairs">&lt;strong>Certification Co-Chairs&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="christopher-erdmannhttpswwwscilifelabsenewsscilifelab-voices-chris-erdmann">
&lt;a href="https://www.scilifelab.se/news/scilifelab-voices-chris-erdmann/">Christopher Erdmann&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Has previously worked for and with many organizations, including; the American Geophysical Union, Renaissance Computing Institute at UNC, California Digital Library (The Carpentries), Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, European Southern Observatory, and the United Nations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Is a community advocate, developer, and experimenter in the areas of Open Science and FAIR&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="sandra-gesinghttpsandra-gesingcom">
&lt;a href="http://sandra-gesing.com/">Sandra Gesing&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Holds dual roles as Executive Director of the US Research Software Engineer Association (US-RSE) and as a Senior Researcher at the San Diego Supercomputer Center, focusing on science gateways, computational workflows, and distributed computing in interdisciplinary contexts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Directs the Center of Excellence for Science Gateways&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Performs advocacy work through US-RSE to promote career paths and recognition for research software engineers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Has held academic and industry positions in the US, UK, and Germany&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="ismael-kherroubi-garciahttpswwwlinkedincominismaelkherroubi">
&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ismaelkherroubi">Ismael Kherroubi Garcia&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Founder and CEO of Kairoi, the AI ethics and research governance consultancy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Founder and co-lead of the Responsible Artificial Intelligence Network (RAIN) at the RSA&lt;/li>
&lt;li>He holds both a bachelor’s in business administration and management, and a master’s in philosophy of the social sciences&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="current-developments">&lt;strong>Current Developments&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The nearly 30 members of the Certification WG are taking a short break from projects after the monumental efforts put into their recent manuscript. New projects and directions will be discussed in the first quarter of 2025.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="previous-projects">&lt;strong>Previous Projects&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Manuscript preparation &amp;lsquo;Ten Simple Rules to Promote Good Model-Sharing Practices&amp;rsquo;. Preprint available through
&lt;a href="https://zenodo.org/records/12665701">Zenodo&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Feb-May 2024: Seven part
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC17zWxzjmfvNV_bCYhOZrsQ">ModelShare&lt;/a> workshop series. Learn more about this project
&lt;a href="https://share.openmodelingfoundation.org/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>About: Cyberinfrastructure Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/cyberinfrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/cyberinfrastructure/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Cyberinfrastructure Working Group (CYWG) coordinates development and management of the OMF Science Gateway, an online platform for collaborative governance and standards. CYWG works to to identify, develop, and enhance tools and processes that lower the technical barriers towards adoption of OMF standards and facilitate their use by modeling scientists. CYWG staff assist the EOWG in developing online training modules and making them available on the OMF Science Gateway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in joining the Cyberinfrastructure Working Group,
&lt;a href="https://asu.questionpro.com/omf-wg-joinrequest">please use this link&lt;/a> or reach our to the group Chair for further information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/openmodelingfoundation/openmodelingfoundation.github.io/discussions/categories/cyberinfrastructure">Contribute to the Cyberinfrastructure Working Group discussion on GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="cyberinfrastructure-chair">&lt;strong>Cyberinfrastructure Chair&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="allen-leehttpsgithubcomalee">
&lt;a href="https://github.com/alee">Allen Lee&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Software and Data Carpentries&amp;rsquo; instructor and lesson maintainer for
&lt;a href="https://swcarpentry.github.io/python-novice-gapminder/">Plotting and Programming in Python&lt;/a>
and
&lt;a href="https://carpentries-lab.github.io/good-enough-practices/">Good Enough Practices in Scientific Computing&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Currently serves on the
&lt;a href="https://datacite.org/stsg/">DataCite Services and Technology Steering Group&lt;/a> and as a co-chair of the
&lt;a href="https://scicodes.net">Consortium of Scientific Software Registries and Repositories&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technical lead and co-director of
&lt;a href="https://comses.net">the Network for Computational Modeling in the Social and Ecological Sciences (CoMSES.Net)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Working towards developing and promoting good enough practices for frictionless reuse in research software for over two decades&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="current-developments">&lt;strong>Current Developments&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Current CYWG work is focused on:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a collaborative effort with partners CSDMS and CUAHSI in assessing FAIR metadata assessments
(e.g.,
&lt;a href="https://inab.github.io/FAIRsoft_indicators/">FAIRsoft indicators&lt;/a> and the
&lt;a href="https://openebench.bsc.es/observatory/">OpenEBench Observatory&lt;/a>
as well as research software quality efforts like the
&lt;a href="https://everse.software/RSQKit/">EVERSE Research Software Quality Kit&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>developing RAG pipelines for LLM-enhanced workflows around computational models in the areas of software quality,
metadata completeness, documentation, tests, interoperability, and model analysis (e.g., sensitivity analysis,
uncertainty quantification, model optimization and calibration)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We welcome new contributors, and are also &lt;strong>
&lt;a href="https://asu.questionpro.com/omf-wg-joinrequest">actively searching for additional co-chairs&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some example work streams we&amp;rsquo;d love to have more hands on deck for include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>improve the UI/UX of the OMF site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>improve the workflows for upgrading and deploying changes to the OMF site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>set up a parallel staging server where we can test changes to the OMF site on GitHub Pages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and last but not least,
&lt;a href="https://asu.questionpro.com/omf-wg-joinrequest">please consider applying to serve as a co-chair&lt;/a>
on the CYWG to help prioritize, coordinate, and manage current and future work streams&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="previous-projects">&lt;strong>Previous Projects&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Establishing the initial OMF website and site infrastructure using Hugo, Docker, Docsy, and GitHub Pages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Establishing communication channels (e.g., Slack, Google Groups, etc.) to facilitate Working Groups coordination&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Establishing the
&lt;a href="https://share.openmodelingfoundation.org/">ModelShare&lt;/a> website on GitHub Pages for the Certification
Working Group&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All of the other plumbing needed to set up external facing websites and science gateways as well as developing
measured and inclusive pathways for community contributions, and staging, testing, and deployment. &lt;em>IYKYK - if you&amp;rsquo;d
like to learn, join us!&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>About: Early Career Scholars Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/early-career-scholars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/early-career-scholars/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Early Career Scholars (ECSWG) helps the Open Modeling Foundation to support student and early career development. The ECSWG is
open to any student enrolled in an institution of higher learning (e.g., college or university) or early career scholar (recent graduate).
The ECSWG provides input to the Executive Committee. The ECSWG can organize student-focused programs, manuscripts, and events, assisted by the Administrative Coordinator and other OMF WG&amp;rsquo;s as appropriate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in joining the Early Career Scholars Working Group,
&lt;a href="https://asu.questionpro.com/omf-wg-joinrequest">please use this link&lt;/a> or reach out to the group Chair for further information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/openmodelingfoundation/openmodelingfoundation.github.io/discussions/categories/early-career-scholars">Contribute to the Early Career Scholars Working Group discussion on GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="early-career-scholars-chair">&lt;strong>Early Career Scholars Chair&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="takuya-iwanagahttpswwwresearchgatenetprofiletakuya-iwanaga-2">
&lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Takuya-Iwanaga-2">Takuya Iwanaga&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Senior Research Scientist within the Australian Institute of Marine Science&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Research Software Developer with the Institute of Water Futures&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="current-developments">&lt;strong>Current Developments&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The almost 40 strong group of OMF Early Career Scholars are focused on developing the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Manuscript for publication of the topic of Good Modeling Practices is currently being revised based upon reviewer feedback&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="previous-projects">&lt;strong>Previous Projects&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Not applicable yet - works are sill in development &amp;ldquo;Watch this space!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About: Education and Outreach Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/education-and-outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/education-and-outreach/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Education and Outreach Working Group (EOWG) helps OMF member organizations reach and train next generation scholars and ensure proactive outreach to groups and nationalities that are underrepresented in modeling science. Depending on available resources, it may develop and deploy educational and training materials, organize workshops, symposia, clinics, and other promotional or engagement events to disseminate OMF standards and help modeling scientists meet those standards. The EOWG coordinates with the SWG to ensure that standards adopted by the OMF are supported by appropriate training and educational programs, and accessible via the OMF Science Gateway. The EOWG coordinates with the OMF Early Career Scholars to develop programs to support early-career scientists. Depending on available resources, such programs may include scholarships to attend trainings in standards-based modeling or presenting standards-based modeling research at professional meetings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in joining the Education and Outreach Working Group,
&lt;a href="https://asu.questionpro.com/omf-wg-joinrequest">please use this link&lt;/a> or reach out to any of the group Co-Chairs for further information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/openmodelingfoundation/openmodelingfoundation.github.io/discussions/categories/wg-education-and-outreach">Contribute to the Education and Outreach discussion on GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="education--outreach-co-chairs">&lt;strong>Education &amp;amp; Outreach Co-Chairs&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="junzhi-liuhttpsscholargooglecomcitationsusereob7fswaaaajhlen">
&lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=eOB7FswAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en">Junzhi Liu&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Professor in the Center for the Pan-Third Pole Environment, Lanzhou University, China.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>He and his team developed the SEIMS (Spatially Explicit Integrated Modeling System) watershed modeling framework and the WISE (Watershed-based Integrated Simulator for the Environment) watershed model.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="iestyn-woolwayhttpswwwbangoracukstaffsosiestyn-woolway-050578en">
&lt;a href="https://www.bangor.ac.uk/staff/sos/iestyn-woolway-050578/en">Iestyn Woolway&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Climate scientist at Bangor University in Wales&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Research focusses on modelling the earth system, with a specific focus on freshwater systems.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="current-developments">&lt;strong>Current Developments&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The nearly 40 members of the Education and Outreach WG are currently working towards a number of goals:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Help communicate between OMF member organizations via OMF News Letter Development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coordinates with the OMF Early Career Scholars to develop programs to support early-career scientists, thus assisting with training the next generation of scholars with an interest in modelling human and natural systems.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Develop and deploy educational and training materials, organize workshops, and other promotional or engagement events to disseminate OMF standards as needed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Development of tutorials on how to implement the FAIR principles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implementing FAIR Principles in Lake Watershed Modelling to Tackle Water Resource and Ecosystem Challenges&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="previous-projects">&lt;strong>Previous Projects&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Newsletter design and preparation&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h5 id="friends-of-the-education-and-outreach-working-group">&lt;strong>Friends of the Education and Outreach Working Group&lt;/strong>&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>We would like to thank and acknolodge the following People and Organizations who have supported WG efforts, projects, or have otherwise been directly or indirectly involved in WG projects or efforts.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://www.cpgis.org/">CPGIS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>About: Standards Working Group</title><link>/about/working-groups/standards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/working-groups/standards/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Standards Working Group (SWG) oversees the adoption, dissemination, and administration of Open Modeling Foundation standards for access, documentation, reusability, and interoperability. It proposes standards to be reviewed, revised, and approved by the OMF Members Council. The SWG works with Administrative Coordinator to communicate proposed and adopted OMF standards to OMF member organizations and other stakeholders, and solicit input about proposed standards from the modeling community. In coordination with the Certification Working Group, it helps OMF member (and other) code repositories implement OMF standards for access, discoverability, and recognition of model developers who implement OMF best practice standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/viewer?url=https://github.com/openmodelingfoundation/openmodelingfoundation.github.io/files/6481459/standards_workflow.pdf" target="_blank">View schematic of potential standards-making workflow&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in joining the Standards Working Group,
&lt;a href="https://asu.questionpro.com/omf-wg-joinrequest">please use this link&lt;/a> or reach out to any of the group Co-Chairs for further information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://github.com/openmodelingfoundation/openmodelingfoundation.github.io/discussions/categories/wg-standards">Contribute to the Standards Working Group discussion on GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="standards-co-chairs">&lt;strong>Standards Co-Chairs&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="volker-grimmhttpswwwufzdeindexphpen36522">
&lt;a href="https://www.ufz.de/index.php?en=36522">Volker Grimm&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ecological modeller and professor of Theoretical Ecology&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Works on modelling methodology, in particular agent-based modelling&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Main developer of the standards ODD and TRACE&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="serena-hamiltonhttpsresearchportalplusanueduauenpersonsserena-hamilton">
&lt;a href="https://researchportalplus.anu.edu.au/en/persons/serena-hamilton">Serena Hamilton&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Focuses on the use of model-based approaches to make better informed decisions about socio-environmental problems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Particularly interested in integrated assessment and modelling for co-production of knowledge in transdisciplinary research, and identifying and promoting best practices in modelling development and evaluation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Managing editor of the open access journal Socio-Environmental Systems Modelling (SESMO)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="geerten-hengeveldhttpsniooknawnlnlemployeesgeerten-hengeveld">
&lt;a href="https://nioo.knaw.nl/nl/employees/geerten-hengeveld">Geerten Hengeveld&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Using models to support people in making sense of socio-ecological systems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Experience in socio-ecological systems across scales and in Experience in model quality assurance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Executive manager of LTER-LIFE – developing an infrastructure where researchers can build digital twins of ecosystems&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="maria-piercehttpswwwthuenendeeninstitutesbaltic-sea-fisheriesstaffscientificpierce-maria-e">
&lt;a href="https://www.thuenen.de/en/institutes/baltic-sea-fisheries/staff/scientific/pierce-maria-e">Maria Pierce&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Ecological modeller and works on modelling and simulation workflows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Currently develops the work area Individual-Based (and other) Modelling at the Thünen Institute of Baltic Sea Fisheries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Participates in expert groups of the International Council for the Exploration of the Sea (ICES)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="current-developments">&lt;strong>Current Developments&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>SWG has more than 50 members. We are working, in sub-groups, on several manuscripts which are meant to prepare the first standards proposed by OMF:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A review of existing modelling standards to identify the main challenges in establishing standards and the main dimensions of the context in which standards are developed and needed (S. Hamilton, C. Rosello).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The development of a non-technical common language, or &amp;ldquo;lingua franca&amp;rdquo;, for short but informative summary descriptions, which would facilitate communication and collaboration between different modelling communities, and with model users (V. Grimm).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The introduction of a tiered approach, where the effort for following Good Modelling Practice should be proportional to the expected impact of the model (G. Hengeveld).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developing a standard format that helps us to be explicit also about hidden model assumptions, i.e. assumptions that are implicit but can still strongly affect model results (B. Edmonds).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Devil’s advocate: It has been tried for decades to establish modelling standards, with limited success so far. Is it impossible? Here we try to identify the main obstacles and thereby learn from the past (A. Voinov).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="previous-projects">&lt;strong>Previous Projects&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Not applicable yet - works are sill in development &amp;ldquo;Watch this space!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>